CURRICULUM VITAE

Personal information:

Surname Berger Name Ernst Jan

Address Sophiastraat 16zwart

Zip code 2011 VW City Haarlem

Mobile +31 (0) 6 43260680

Email ernstjanberger@gmail.com

LinkedIn http://www.linkedin.com/in/ernstjanberger

Twitter @ejberger & @BanenInTechniek

Date of birth 26-01-1986
Place of birth Leidschendam
Marital status Unmarried partners

Nationality Dutch Driver's licence B

Profile:

Recruitment professional with extensive experience in recruitment, sourcing, business development and relationship management. A enthusiastic networker with a sincere interest in people and their motivations. Result driven, eye for organizational development, promotion and staffing leadership. Experienced employment market communicator, user of several recruitment tools and KPI based performance. Able to translate organizational strategy into recruitment and sourcing tactics.

Education:

2006 - 2010	Bachelor of Commerce with a minor Spanish, Hogeschool van Amsterdam (HES).
2005 - 2006	Business Administration, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam.
2004 - 2005	Business Administration, Erasmus Universiteit Rotterdam.
1998 - 2004	Vwo (Higher General Secondary Education) Economy and Society with a minor
	Management and Organisation, Erasmus College Zoetermeer.

Training and workshops:

2012	Sales & Personal Branding, Exsista by Roberto van Rikxoort.
2011	Boolean Search and Sourcing, W3Recruitment by Gordon Lokenberg.
2009	Information Systems Foundation A, Hogeschool NOVI.
2008	Search Engine Optimizing and Advertising, Otys Recruitment Software.
2008	Advanced Sourcing, by Dave Mendoza.

Professional experience:

2013 - now **Interim Sourcer & Corporate Recruiter,** Accenture, Amsterdam.

I'm responsible for sourcing and recruiting professionals for a consultancy project for a large client of Accenture within the Asset Management domain. I'm also responsible for sourcing for different business units within Accenture Technology Solutions. Fulfilled roles: Testers, Capital Markets Specialists (Murex specialized: development and support), Business Intelligence Consultants (SAS specialized), Application Manager Fund Accounting, Project Manager Financial Services, SAP Consultants (SD, MM, PLM, PM, EAM, Security, GRC, BPC), JAVA Architects, JAVA Developers, Python Developers, Front-End Developers, SOA BPM Consultants, Technical Architects, DWH Architects, BI (DWH) Developers with experience within the Financial Services Industry, E-Commerce Developers, Application Services Account Executives and many more.

2013 - now Interim Recruiter Engineering & IT, Ernst Jan Berger Consultancy Amsterdam. I'm specialized in sourcing and recruiting Engineering and IT professionals but I have also in-depth knowledge of other candidate profiles. Please contact me for a tailor

made solution that will exceed your demands.

2013 - now **Founder and Recruiter,** Search It Recruitment by, Amsterdam.

We are internationally active and specialized in recruiting IT & Engineering professionals for permanent, contracting and temporary vacancies / assignments. We like to deliver extra value to the business successes of our clients and the careers of professionals. Next to recruiting I'm responsible for sales, account management, software/hardware structure and managing my colleagues.

2010 - 2013 **Managing Consultant and Senior Recruiter Engineering**, Independent Engineering, Amsterdam.

I was given the opportunity to create and manage a new label within the Independent Recruiters Group. With Independent Engineering I managed to close contracts with technical companies for permanent and interim jobs. With the assistance of other teams IT, Finance, Sales & Marketing we were able to fulfil almost every position at engineering clients. Besides new business development and relationship management I was accountable for candidate sourcing, screening, interviewing and preparing them for interviews. In 2012 and 2013 I was also asked by LinkedIn and Broadbean to give workshops about their recruitment tools and sourcing at HRM and recruitment events.

2009 - 2011 **Senior Recruiter IT and Engineering,** Independent Recruiters Group, Amsterdam. I was responsible for the entire recruitment and sales process in finding suitable candidates for several clients within different fields of expertise and industries. My annual target was 85K and I managed to more than double this in 2010 and 2011.

2008 - 2009 Marketing Manager, Independent Recruiters Group, Amsterdam. As a marketing manager I was responsible for analysing and fine-tuning Independent Recruiters Otys Recruitment software, multi posting software and several sourcing tools. I optimised all computer applications and the websites next to externally posted job advertisements. This resulted in a higher PageRank within search engines and an optimised recruitment and sales process.

2007 - 2008 **Entrepreneur**, Stylevol Lead Generating Agency, Amsterdam. Stylevol was a lead generator active within the online coupon business. I was responsible for approaching (by phone and door-to-door sales) and delivering our

online products to several retailers, restaurants and sport centres in Amsterdam and The Hague.

2007 - 2007 Broker and Account Manager Electricity and Gas, Lowlands Energy Brokers,

Amsterdam.

Responsible for trading intraday and long term Electricity and Gas contracts within several energy markets. I was a broker for clients such as JP Morgan, Goldman Sachs, Essent, Nuon, Electrabel, EON, Delta, Oxxio, Gasunie and Nidera.

Computer skills:

LinkedIn Recruiter Products, Otys, Oracle Taleo, Broadbean, Knollenstein, Smart Recruiters, Search Software, People XS, iGrasp, MrSearch, Apple OS X, Microsoft OS, Microsoft Office, Google Apps, CMS web design applications, Wordpress, Adobe CS4, SEO, SEA, SEM, Boolean search and many more.

Languages:

Dutch: Native
English: Fluent
German: Good
Spanish: Average
French: Average
Italian: Elementary
Latin: Elementary

Hobbies and interests:

Travelling, running, bicycle racing, golf, tennis, sailing, snowboarding, fitness, ice hockey and food.

Recruitment fields of expertise:

- ➤ IT
- > Engineering
- Consultancy
- > Management
- ➤ Sales & Marketing
- ➤ Recruitment & HRM
- > Finance
- Procurement

Recruitment expertise in the following industries:

- > IT / Software, Web Development and Infrastructure
- > IT Consultancy / System Integrators
- > Energy
- Maritime
- ➤ Industrial Automation
- > Research & Development
- Civil
- Pharma / Food
- > Financial Institutions

References on request